hi everybody welcome back to the channel
now I mentioned this ice cream a few
weeks ago this is one that was inspired
by all the Johnny Depp and Amber Heard
stuff blah blah blah that was going on
for weeks and weeks and weeks and end
I'm a big Johnny Depp fan and the
Pirates of the Caribbean films have
become a bit of a staple for you know I
think a few Generations now they're
they're perfectly watchable and Captain
Jack Sparrow is a bloody good character
so
we thought it would be fun to make a
Jack Sparrow inspired ice cream
and as a pirate they all used to drink I
mean they didn't really used to drink
rum a lot it was mainly beer that they
used drink in reality but in the films
the question always comes up is why is
the rum always gone I'm a big rum
Drinker I've got a few of them here and
I thought it would be fun to use all
three of these types in the ice cream
itself so we've got a Lambs vanilla rum
I mean this technically isn't rum it's a
rum based liqueur because it's under 40
percent
um so we've got an ice cream made with
this we've got some truffles made with
this which is really strong stuff this
is 54 and a half percent
ABV and then this which goes into a
caramel sauce so if you're ready to
watch me get sloshed
let's see how I made it
[Music]
so for the ice cream base we're gonna
start with our milk add in our egg yolks
and our sugar now I've reduced the sugar
a little bit in here just because I'm
putting 50 grams of the rum the Lambs
vanilla rum in here now obviously I've
used the Lambs because it's very heavy
vanilla flavor and I'm making vanilla
ice cream so it kind of goes hand in
hand
once you've added all the ingredients
and your sugar's dissolved you've added
your skimmed milk powder
you've got it up to temperature now
obviously because we're using egg yolks
I'd probably recommend getting it up to
the 70 degree C Mark just to cook those
egg yolks finally turn the heat off and
then add in your rum get it nicely
combined put it in a container and then
put it in the fridge to chill down
so these rum truffles now get prepared
with your rum I've called these gun
powder rum truffles the actual rum
itself is called gunpowder proof it's a
spiced rum it's really strong so we're
gonna take our double cream and warm it
up gently in the microwave you can do
this on the hob if you want to pour that
over your milk chocolate and butter make
sure your chocolate then fully melts and
then finally add in your rum This Is 50
mils worth of that dark really strong
rum here when it's all completely melted
and ready pour it into a lined cake tin
this is an eight by eight Square just
whatever you've got to hand is fine and
put it in the fridge just to solidify up
now after your truffle is completely
chilled down from being in the fridge
you can take it out and start molding it
into these little cute bowls and I am
going to coat these in guitars cocoa
powder it's really really nice cocoa
powder not too bitter really nice strong
flavor so just roll that truffle between
your hands obviously I'm using gloves
it's really really messy stuff and then
drop them in the cocoa powder make sure
they're fully covered put them in a
little container keep them in the fridge
until we're ready to load up their tub
foreign
[Music]
part to this ice cream is The Sparrows
rum caramel now it should go without
saying why I've chosen Sparrow's rum but
you know just in case Jack Sparrow and
all that so we're gonna make a wet
caramel here and what that means is
we're adding water to the sugar put the
sugar in the water in the pan get that
moving around and combined and start the
sugar dissolving that way then gently
turn the heat on and then bring it up to
a color that you think is right I'm
gonna say once you're happy with the
color turn the heat off because it will
continue cooking just a little bit more
after that then you can add in your room
temperature butter and your cream once
that's nicely combined finally add in
the rum 80 grams worth of sparrows rum
has gone into this so this is a really
strong stuff
make sure that it's nicely mixed and
then put it in a container keep it at
room temperature until we're ready to go
[Music]
and the final part here is once your ice
cream base is chilled take it out the
fridge and put it in your machine as
normal now this might take a little
longer in your machine to churn with
this much alcohol in that's one reason
why we drop the sugar slightly
when it's ready you can take your
truffles out the fridge you can get your
caramel ready get it all ready and then
start loading up and layer in a really
nice mix of caramel
chop your truffles in half if they're
big like mine or whatever size you want
to put in there give it a nice little
mix make sure it's fully combined and
that caramel is laced throughout put the
lid on the tub and put it in a freezer
for at least six hours here
[Music]
so there are a few bits to this video
you're making you know the truffles
you're making the caramel sauce you're
making a rum ice cream this is not a
vanilla ice cream per se it's a rum ice
cream obviously you've seen me put the
vanilla in it that's just a boost of
flavors of this because you know vanilla
extract still is a stronger flavor than
vanilla flavored something so just boost
that flavor a little bit it's been in
the freezer for us overnight just
family life gets in the way so we're
going to get some out move these bottles
aside and get some scooped up and see
how strong this really is
[Music]
now before I put this back in the
freezer I just want to
congratulate my wife on what is possibly
the best tub that she has ever done
you've got the Black Pearl Jack Sparrow
beach scene palm trees Sunbirds it's
amazing if you like the tubs my wife
does for our videos make sure to pop a
like here and let us know on social
media because she doesn't get a chance
to do them a lot you know with a with a
toddler taking up a lot of our time and
we also have another business that we
run these sometimes take a back seat so
I'm really glad we got this one out it's
half past one on Sunday afternoon and
there's so much alcohol in this
I'm not sure I'll be able to drive
anywhere after having this let's see
what the ice cream on its own tastes
like first
it's subtle you don't get that punch of
rum the Lambs is quite
it's quite an easy going run like I said
it's not technically rum so it's much
easier to drink and in this ice cream it
boosts the vanilla flavor but you get a
really nice warming effect to it
something to mention when you use
alcohol and ice creams is don't use too
much the freezing point depression of
alcohol is is quite a strong effect so
if you are putting more in you're gonna
have to reduce the sugar somewhat but
also it will speed up the melting
process it's melting in the bowl
half of that is in fact it's bloody
boiling hot today but the other part of
it is the alcohol
so try and get some of this caramel and
see how that blends in it as well
[Music]
that
caramel is strong
well I like it
it's
um
so this is The Sparrows it's 40 ABV it's
pretty decent it's not uh amazing it's a
nice comfortable drink to have on its
own or a Coke
goes really well with that caramel and
cuts through because that vanilla
Lambs vanilla ice cream is quite subtle
you get that Streaker caramel going
through it
and then you know exactly what you've
made now I'm gonna dig into one of these
truffles
now
gum powder proof
rum 55 54.5 ABV
make some stonking good truffles
I'm gonna try one without being anything
man they're strong
it's what you want from this
you're making a rum-based ice cream
you're making a raw ice cream with rum
Truffles and rum caramel what do you
want the flavor of rum why is the rum
always gone well it's not in here it's
everywhere in here
really really strong run flavor
my wife says she can smell it just me
breathing
now if you don't like rum
just substitute all of these for your
favorite drink it's if you like whiskey
go for whiskey you could probably do a
nice complex whiskey mix of flavors here
if you don't like any of those kind of
spirits I mean you know white rum I'm
not a massive fan of
but you could you'd obviously change the
flavor profile because the majority of
it is coconut flavored but
you know just mix and match with
whatever alcohol you like you could you
could you could do this with beers and
Ales if you really wanted to and as I
said Pirates historically did drink more
of that than rum rum was something that
they would try and create and actually
in reality they wouldn't have drank any
of these
they would have had a very white rum
because that's what was available back
in the time it was made with whatever
they had
but majority of the time it was beer
that they drank I don't like beer I
don't like beer lager or ale so I'm
unlikely to make anything with those
Never Say Never though I mean if you
watch this channel long enough I've made
some weird over the last couple of
years
and actually interestingly enough
there's some more really weird ones
coming up this year we've done the
planning I have made possibly the
strangest ice cream I've ever made my
wife didn't like it I
didn't to start with but actually really
liked it after that you get past this
little weird mentality of it but we've
got a lot of nice ice cream flavors and
interesting ice cream flavors coming up
so make sure you like And subscribe and
I'm gonna maybe hit this whole serving
of ice cream on a Sunday afternoon so
thanks very much see you next week
[Music]
thank you